Register of the Joan Beecher Eichrodt collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Research Materials, 1872-2002 (Boxes 8-23)
  - Soviet Union, 1985-1991
    - International relations, 1983-1986, undated (Box-folder 19: 8-14)
      Includes interview with Wolfgang Leonhard.
    - Putnik scandal, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic (RSFSR), 1986-1992
      - General, 1991 (Box-folder 19: 16-22)
      - Constitution, 1990 (Box-folder 19: 23-26)
      - Economy, 1986, 1990 (Box-folder 19: 27)
      - Elections, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 19: 28-34)
      - Nationalism, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 1-7)
      - S"ezd predstaviteleĭ narodov, ne imeiushchikh svoeĭ gosudarstvennosti, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 8)
      - Sovereignty, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 9-12)
    - Social movements, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 13-17)
    - Strategic Defense Initiative, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 20: 18-20)
    - Supreme Soviet, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 20: 21-26)
    - Tatarstan, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 27)
    - Uzbekistan, 1990 (Box-folder 20: 28)
    - Yeltsin, Boris, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 20: 29-30)
  - Sufism, 1998 (Box-folder 20: 31-32)
  - Writings by others, 1872-2002
    Photocopies
    - Anishchenko, Gleb, "Kto vinovat?,", 1988 January (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Aronzon, Leonid, Stikhotvoreniia, Leningrad: Leningradskiĭ komitet literatorov, 1990 (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Avtorkhanov, Abdurakhman, Narodoubiĭstvo v SSSR: ubiĭstvo chechenskogo naroda, Munich: Svobodnyĭ Kavkaz, 1952 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - Baddelay, John F., The Russian Conquest of the Caucasus, London: Longman's, 1908 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Berzhe, A. P. Chechnia i chechentsy: sochinenie Pravitelia del Kavkazskogo otdela Imperatorskogo Russkogo Geograficheskogo obshchestva, Tiflis, 1859, Groznyĭ: Knizhnoe izdadetel'stvo, 1991 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Bliev, M. M., "Kavkazskaia voina: sotsial'nye istoki, sushchnost',", 1994 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Bunich, Igor', Khronika chechenskoĭ boĭni i shest' dneĭ v Budennovske, St. Petersburg: Oblik, 1995 (Box-folder 21: 7-8)
    - Dal', Vladimir Ivanovich, Zapiska o ritual'nykh ubiĭstvakh, St. Petersburg, 1913 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, Ocherki russkoĭ smuty, Moscow: Mysl', 1991 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - Derlugian, Georgi M., "The Accidental Quagmire: Reassessing Chechnia's War of Independence," United States Institute of Peace, 1997 June 19 (Box-folder 21: 11)
    - Donskoĭ, F. S., "Aktual'nye problemy obespecheniia polnoĭ zaniatosti narodnosteĭ Severa obshchestvenno-poleznym trudom," Akademiia nauk SSSR-Sibirskoe otdelenie, Iakutsk, 1990 (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - Dzagurov, G. A., Pereselenie gortsev v Turtsiiu: materialy po istorii gorskikh narodov, Rostov-Don: Sevkavkniga, 1978 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - Dzidzariia, G. A., Makhadzhirstvo i problemy istorii Abkhazii XIX stoletiia, Sukhumi: Alashara, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 14)
    - Gayton, Jeffrey T., "Federalism and Sovereignty in the Russian Federation: An Analysis of Regionalism and Centralism in Russian State-Building," University of Wisconsin, 1994 May 16 (Box-folder 21: 15)
    - Gol'dshteĭn, Arkadiĭ, Bashni v gorakh, Moscow: Sovetskiĭ khudozhnik, 1977 (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
    - Henze, Paul, 1971, 1991-1995
      Consists of reports, articles, and memoranda.
      - "Conflict in the Caucasus: Background, Problems, and Prospects for Mitigation,", 1993 February 4 (Box-folder 22: 3)
      - "Georgia in 1995: Recovery Gaining Momentum,", 1995 October (Box-folder 22: 4)
      - "International Alert's Fact-Finding Mission to Chechnia,", 1992 October (Box-folder 22: 5)
      - Memorandum on trip to Georgia, 1992 December 29 (Box-folder 22: 6)
      - "Russia and the Chechens: Background to the Confrontations of 1991-1992,", 1992 June (Box-folder 22: 7)
      - "The Shamil Problem,", 1971 (Box-folder 22: 8)
      - "Strategic Appraisal: Caucasus and Central Asia as of mid-1994, updated to March 1995,", circa 1995 (Box-folder 22: 9)
      - "United States Interests in the Caucasus,", 1991 November (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Human Rights Watch, "Welcome to Hell: Arbitrary Detention, Torture and Extortion in Chechnia,", 2000 October (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Khetagurov, Kosta (Konstantin Khetagkati), Publitsistika: izbrannye stat'i, Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo Severo-osetinskoi ASSR, 1941 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Kovalevskii, M. M., Zakon i obychai na Kavkaze, Moscow, 1890 (Box-folder 22: 13)
    - Kusakov, N., "Pravoslavie i monarkhiia," Nash Zhurnal, no. 1, 1969 May-June (Box-folder 22: 14)
    - Kul'chik, Iu. G., "Etnopoliticheskaia situatsiia v Dagestane v nachale 1995 goda,", circa 1995 (Box-folder 22: 15)
    - Lakoba, S. Z., Ocherki politicheskoĭ istorii Abkhazii, Sukhumi: Alashara, 1990 (Box-folder 22: 16)
    - Laudaev, U. "Chechenskoe plemia," Sbornik svedeniĭ o kavkazskikh gortsakh, Vypusk VII, 1872 (Box-folder 22: 17)
    - Lavrov, L. N., "Problemy etnogeneza kavkazskikh gortsev," Istoriko-etnograficheskie ocherki Kavkaza, Leningrad, 1978 (Box-folder 22: 18)
    - Leighton, Lauren G., Alexander Bestuzhev-Marlinsky, New York: Twayne Publishers, 1975 (Box-folder 22: 19)
    - Mamardashvili, M. K., "Problema soznaniia i filosofskoe prizvanie," Voprosy filosofii, no. 8, 1987 (Box-folder 22: 20)
    - Mech, Sergeĭ, Kavkaz, Moscow: A.I. Mamontov, 1884 (Box-folder 22: 21)
    - Memorial Tsentr, Cherez dva goda posle voiny: problema vynuzhdennykh pereselentsev v zone osetino-ingushskogo konflikta, Moscow: Memorial, 1994 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - Murray, Edmund P., "Banking on Democracy in Dagestan," Hoboken: Ed Murray Associates, undated (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - Muzaev, Timur, "The General's Trump, or How the 'Imperial Threat' Saves Dudaev,", 1992 September 25 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - Nokhchua, Iusup, Stranitsy istorii chechenskogo naroda, Groznyĭ: Kniga, 1993 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Petrov, Nikolai, "Ethnic-Territorial Conflicts in the Former USSR and Possibilities for Their Regulation,", undated (Box-folder 23: 5)
      Includes clipping from the Neue Zürcher Zeitung on Abkhazia.
    - Pol', Mikaela, "Neuzheli eti zemli nasheĭ mogiloĭ stanut? Chechentsy i ingushi v Kazakhstane," 1944-1957, Diaspora, no. 2, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Ryvkina, R. V., "Puti sovershenstvovaniia sotsiial'nogo mekhanizma razvitiia sovetskoĭ ekonomiki: sbornik nauchnykh trudov," Novosibirsk: Akademiia nauk SSSR, Sibirskoe otdelenie, 1985 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Sahlins, Marshall David, Tribesmen, Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1978 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Shafarevich, I. R., "Rusofobiia," Veche, 1989 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Sheripov, E. A., "Obychnoe pravo, nravstvennost', zakon,", undated (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Talbot, Strobe, "A Farewell to Flashman: American Policy in the Caucasus and Central Asia," speech at Johns Hopkins, 1997 July 21 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - Terskiĭ sbornik, 1892-1893, 1903
      - "Bibliograficheskiĭ spisok,", 1892 (Box-folder 23: 12)
      - "Ingushi,", 1892 (Box-folder 23: 13)
      - "Kabardintsy,", 1892 (Box-folder 23: 14)
      - "Karanogaĭtsy,", 1893 (Box-folder 23: 15)
      - "Ocherki narodnykh obychaev Kumykov,", 1892 (Box-folder 23: 16)
      - "Osetiny,", 1892 (Box-folder 23: 17)
      - "Piat' gorskikh obshchestv Kabardy," Vypusk V, 1903 (Box-folder 23: 18)
    - Urnov, M. Iu., "Politicheskoe soznanie narodnykh deputatov RSFSR,", circa 1990 (Box-folder 23: 19)
    - Vasil'eva, Ol'ga, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 23: 20-24)
      Includes "Russkie kak natsional'noe men'shinstvo" and interviews with Sergeĭ Popov, Murat Karaketov and Bilal Laĭpanov.
    - Wolf, Frank, "Tragedy in Chechnia,", 1996 July 12 (Box-folder 23: 25)
- Clippings, 1989-1995 (Box 24)
  Relates to Islam in the Caucasus, the war in Chechnia, Chechen-Russian relations, Chechen and Ingush politicians, and national sovereignty. Maintained in Eichrodt's original order: by publication location and then alphabetically by newspaper title.
  - Newspapers from the Caucasus, 1992-1994, undated
    - Golos Chechenskoĭ Respubliki, 1992 July 29, 1993 March 16, undated (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Ichkeriia, 1993 June 6 - December 30 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - Impul's, 1993 February 4 and April 22 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Kavkaz, 1991 December 15 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Nazranovets (Na'sarkho), 1991 November 7 and December 10 and 21 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Respublika, 1992 May 29 (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Serdalo, 1992 October 29 (Box-folder 24: 7)
    - Spravedlivost', 1992 June, 1993 November, 1994 January (Box-folder 24: 8)
    - Terkiĭst, 1992 May 16 (Box-folder 24: 9)
    - Unidentified, 1992 September 6, undated (Box-folder 24: 10)
  - Newspapers from the RSFSR and the Russian Federation, 1989-1995
    - Anarkhist, no. 2, 1989 (Box-folder 24: 11)
    - Argumenty i fakty, 1995 April-June (Box-folder 24: 12)
    - Golodovka, 1989 September and October (Box-folder 24: 13)
    - Izvestiia, 1995 March-June (Box-folder 24: 14-16)
    - Komsomol'skaia pravda, 1995 June 1 (Box-folder 24: 17)
    - Literaturnaia Rossiia, 1990 March 2 (Box-folder 24: 18)
    - Moskovskie novosti, 1995 April-July (Box-folder 24: 19)
    - Nezavisimaia gazeta, 1995 March-May (Box-folder 24: 20)
    - Novoe vremia, 1994 August-September (Box-folder 24: 21)
    - Panorama, 1990 July (Box-folder 24: 22)
    - Philanthropist, 1995 April (Box-folder 24: 23)
    - Rossiia, 1995 May 31 - June 6 (Box-folder 24: 24)
    - Rossiĭskaia gazeta, 1995 April-June (Box-folder 24: 25-26)
    - Segodnia, 1995 March-June (Box-folder 24: 27-32)
    - Sovetskaia Rossiia, 1995 April-July (Box-folder 24: 33)
    - Trud, 1995 June 9 (Box-folder 24: 34)
    - Zavtra, 1995 January and March (Box-folder 24: 35)
    - Unidentified, 1990, 1992, 1994, 1995, undated (Box-folder 24: 36)
  - United States, 1995 February 16
    - New York Review of Books (Box-folder 24: 37)
- Notebooks, 1987-1996, undated (Boxes 25-31)
  Consists of Eichrodt's interview and research notes. Arranged alphabetically by Eichrodt's notebook title.
  - Abkhazia, undated (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Abkhaz conflict, undated (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Alma-Ata, undated (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Appointment calendar, 1995 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Baku, undated (Box-folder 25: 5-6)
  - Baturin on glasnost' and USSR Congress notes, 1991 September (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Bicheldeĭ interview, Demokraticheskaia Rossiia and a hearing on nationalities, 1991 May-July (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Chechnia, 1992-1993, 1995, undated
    - 1992 September (Box-folder 25: 9-10)
    - 1993 May (Box-folder 25: 11)
    - 1995 April-May (Box-folder 25: 12)
    - 1995 August (Box-folder 25: 13)
    - undated (Box-folder 25: 14-15)
  - Chechnia and Ingushetia, undated (Box-folder 25: 16)
  - Dagestan, 1996 (Box-folder 25: 17)
  - Demokraticheskaia Rossiia, undated (Box-folder 25: 18)
  - Dushanbe, undated (Box-folder 25: 19)
  - Dushanbe questions, undated (Box-folder 25: 20)
  - Georgia, undated (Box-folder 25: 21)
  - Georgia, Vladikavkaz and Nal'chik, 1992 September (Box-folder 25: 22)
  - Goncharenko interview, 1991 October 29 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Ingushetia, 1993, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 26: 2-6)
  - Ingushetia and Chechnia, 1993 May-June (Box-folder 26: 7-8)
  - Ingushetia and Dagestan, undated (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Ivanov interview, undated (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Kadets, undated (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Latvian People's Front, 1989 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Leningrad, undated (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Mikhaĭlov interview, undated (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - Monarchists, undated (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - Moscow trips, 1989, undated
    - 1989 March (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - 1989 September (Box-folder 26: 17)
    - 1989 October (Box-folder 26: 18)
    - undated (Box-folder 26: 19)
  - North Ossetia, 1993 February (Box-folder 26: 20)
  - Peoples' Congress, undated (Box-folder 26: 21)
  - Round table and Leningrad trip, undated (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Round table, Peoples' deputies, Osipov interview, Christian Democrats Conference, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - RSFSR, undated (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Russian parliament, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - School of Advanced International Studies, 1989 February (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Social democrats, interview with Krupnik, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Social democrats, undated (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Soviet trip, 1989 March (Box-folder 27: 8-11)
  - Summit, 1990 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Tashkent, 1987 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Tashkent and Davos, 1992 (Box-folder 27: 14)
  - Television notes, 1993 (Box-folder 27: 15)
  - Ukraine, undated (Box-folder 27: 16)
  - USSR, 1990 October, 1991 (Box-folder 27: 17-18)
  - Vilnius, undated (Box-folder 27: 19)
  - Voice of America, 1987-1994, undated
    - General, undated (Box-folder 28: 1-18)
    - Anders, Aslund, 1990 (Box-folder 28: 19)
    - Azerbaijan hearing, undated (Box-folder 28: 20)
    - Baltics, 1987 (Box-folder 28: 21)
    - Dagestan, undated (Box-folder 28: 22)
    - Goble, Paul, 1988 (Box-folder 29: 1)
    - Horn of Africa, undated (Box-folder 29: 2)
    - IMF Forum, 1993 (Box-folder 29: 3)
    - Khalilzad, Zalmay, 1989 April 19 (Box-folder 29: 4)
    - Matlock, Jack, 1991 (Box-folder 29: 5)
    - Medvedev, Nikolai, interview, 1992 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Nagorno-Karabakh hearing, undated (Box-folder 29: 7)
    - OSCE hearings, undated (Box-folder 29: 8)
    - Party conference, 1988 (Box-folder 29: 9)
    - Petrov, 1994 (Box-folder 29: 10-11)
    - Roundtable, 1990 October (Box-folder 29: 12)
    - Roundtable with Federov, undated (Box-folder 29: 13)
    - Russian elections, undated (Box-folder 29: 14)
    - Soviet military, undated (Box-folder 29: 15)
    - Soviet Party Conference, undated (Box-folder 29: 16)
    - Sufi materials, undated (Box-folder 29: 17)
    - Tallinn, 1991 (Box-folder 29: 18)
  - Untitled, 1990s (Box-folder 29: 19-21, 30: 1-8, 31: 1-11)
- Photographs, 1987, 1990s, undated (Boxes 32-33)
  Photographs taken by Eichrodt during her research trips to the Caucasus. Grouped by location.
  - General Caucasus, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 1-12)
    Photographs from unidentified locations in the Caucasus. Subjects include soldiers, street demonstrations, unidentified individuals giving speeches, assemblies, churches, nature, family gatherings, and Joan Beecher Eichrodt.
  - Abkhazia, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 13-14)
    Subjects include tanks, a church, a Christmas party with an unidentified family, and portraits of Joan Beecher Eichrodt.
  - Chechnia, 1987, 1993, undated
    - Street demonstrations and corpses, 1990s (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - Dzhokhar Dudaev portrait and an assembly of Chechen men, 1990s (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - Unidentified family portraits, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - Tolstoĭ-Iurt, 1990s (Box-folder 33: 4)
      Subjects include nature and an unidentified family.
  - Dagestan, 1987 (Box-folder 33: 5-6)
    Subjects include nature, architecture, an unidentified family, and Joan Beecher Eichrodt.
  - Georgia, 1987, undated (Box-folder 33: 7-16)
    Subjects include nature, a wedding, churches, a cemetery, collapsed buildings, and Joan Beecher Eichrodt.
  - Ingushetia, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 17-18)
    Subjects include nature, public gatherings, and portraits of Ruslan Aushev.
  - Moscow demonstration, Red Square, early 1990s (Box-folder 33: 19)
    Includes a photograph of Iuriĭ Baturin and demonstrators from Soiuz russkogo naroda.
  - Joan Beecher Eichrodt and others, undated (Box-folder 33: 20)
- Sound Recordings, 1988-1999 (Boxes 34-40)
  Consists primarily of interviews and Voice of America reports from the Caucasus. Individual cassette tapes may have fragments of multiple interviews; the content of the tapes may include more than the listed title. Unless otherwise indicated, all Voice of America reports and interviews were conducted by Eichrodt. Grouped by interview location, then ordered chronologically.
  - Abkhazia, 1992-1996, undated
    - Iuriĭ Shanibov on national groups in Abkhazia and the Russian presence in the North Caucasus, 1992 September (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Female Abkhaz refugees on the conflict between Georgia and Abkhazia, 1992 September 16 (Box-folder 34: 2)
      Includes a discussion of the refugee situation in Sochi.
    - Natella Akaba on the Abkhaz independence movement, 1992 December 10 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - Natella Akaba, 1993 August 25 (Box-folder 34: 4)
      See Box 3, Folder 2 for transcript.
    - Zurab Achba, 1993 August 28 (Box-folder 34: 5)
      See Box 3, Folder 1 for transcript.
    - Viktor Anatolevich Loginov, 1993 August 29 (Box-folder 34: 6-7)
      See Box 3, Folder 28 for transcript. Includes continuation of interview with Zurab Achba.
    - Sergeĭ Shamba, 1993 October 23 (Box-folder 34: 8)
      See Box 3, Folder 11 for transcript.
    - Press conference on Abkhaz-Georgian relations, 1995 January 20 (Box-folder 34: 9)
    - Iuriĭ Shanibov, 1995 August 14, undated (Box-folder 34: 10-12)
      See Box 6, Folder 19 for partial transcripts.
    - Konstantin Konstantinovich Ozgan, circa 1996 (Box-folder 34: 13)
      Topics include the Abkhaz economy, politics, and relations between the Cossacks of southern Russia with peoples of the North Caucasus.
    - Volunteers in the Abkhaz war, undated (Box-folder 34: 14-15)
      See Box 6, Folder 20 for partial transcripts.
  - Adygea, 1993
    - International Circassian Association meeting, 1993 July 20 (Box-folder 34: 16)
      Speeches and discussions on the development of Circassian national identity and relations with other peoples of the North Caucasus.
    - Shapsug politician on the establishment of the Shapsugskiĭ raĭon in Adygea, 1993 July 20 (Box-folder 34: 17-18)
    - Kazbek Achmiz on negotiations between Russians and Adygei, 1993 July 24 (Box-folder 34: 19)
      Includes speeches from the International Circassian Association meeting.
  - Chechnia, 1991-1999, undated
    - Aslambek Aslakhanov on Chechen domestic politics, 1991 November 21, 1992 (Box-folder 34: 20-21)
    - Magomed Bashir Almazov and a Chechen state secretary, 1992 January (Box-folder 34: 22-23)
      Topics include the Communist party in Chechnia, border disputes between Chechnia and Ingushetia, relations with Cossacks, and cultural memory in Groznyĭ.
    - Dzhokhar Dudaev, 1992 January (Box-folder 34: 24-25)
      Topics include the Chechen economy, citizenship in Chechnia, relations between Chechens and Ingush, reorganization of the political structure, opposition movements in Chechnia, environmental damage, and Stalin's 1944 deportations of Chechens and Ingush.
    - Ali Eskiev, member of a Chechen Islamic party, 1992 January (Box-folder 34: 26)
      Topics include sharia law in Chechnia and the role of Islam in government. Includes a Voice of America report on the declaration of Chechen independence.
    - Television report on the Chechen parliament, 1992 January 14 (Box-folder 34: 27)
    - Bektimar Mezhidov, Chechen parliamentarian, 1992 February (Box-folder 34: 28)
      Topics include Dzhokhar Dudaev, Chechen domestic politics, and United States politics.
    - Georgiĭ Galkin, Cossack ataman, 1992 February (Box-folder 34: 29)
      Topics include Chechen-Ingush relations, Cossack-Chechen relations, and politics in the North Caucasus.
    - Shamil' Beno on Chechen politics, 1992 February 5 (Box-folder 34: 30)
      Includes a discussion of various religions and nationalities in the Caucasus.
    - Dzhokhar Dudaev, 1992 September 15 (Box-folder 34: 31)
      On relations with the Russian Federation, Chechen politics, and conflicts in the Caucasus.
    - Movladi Udugov and the Chechen Ministry of Foreign Affairs group interview, 1992 September 15 (Box-folder 34: 32-33)
      Topics include democracy in the Caucasus, Chechen identity, and the question of genocide in Chechnia during the Stalin era.
    - Kotiev on the 1944 deportations of Chechens and Ingush, 1993 February 13 (Box-folder 34: 34)
      Kotiev describes being deported to Kazakhstan at the age of 5.
    - Vakhit Akaev and Khadzhi-Murat Ibragimbeĭli press conference, 1993 February 19 (Box-folder 34: 35-37)
      Topics include the budget in Chechnia, Dzhokhar Dudaev's regime, and the war between Abkhazia and Georgia.
    - Gorokhov, a Russian member of a veterans' organization in Chechnia, 1993 May 20 (Box-folder 34: 38)
      On his Soviet military career and retirement in Chechnia.
    - Petimat Burdzhiva and Timurlan Mutaliev, 1993 May 21 (Box-folder 34: 39)
      The civilian Burdzhiva describes her wartime experiences. The Ingush historian Mutaliev discusses his career.
    - Lecha Umkhaev and Salambek Khadzhiev, 1993 May 26 (Box-folder 34: 40)
      See Box 4, Folder 18 for a partial transcript.
    - Conference on Chechen domestic politics, 1993 May 29 (Box-folder 34: 41)
    - Abdulla Vatsuev on Chechen domestic affairs, 1993 May 30 (Box-folder 34: 42)
    - Makhmud Bogadov on the Chechen parliament, 1993 May 31 (Box-folder 35: 1)
    - Chechen opposition group members on democracy and elections in Chechnia, 1993 May 31 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - Iusup Soslambekov and Bislan Gantamirov press conference, 1993 June 2 (Box-folder 35: 3)
      Topics include opposition to Dzhokhar Dudaev, Chechen domestic politics, and relations with the Russian Federation.
    - Khaziev, a Chechen ethnologist, 1993 June 3 (Box-folder 35: 4)
      Topics include customs, practices and morality in Chechnia, the differences between sharia law and adat, and the social position of women.
    - Khadzhi-Murat Ibragimbeĭli press conference, 1993 July 9 (Box-folder 35: 5)
      Topics include the Chechen parliament and Dzhokhar Dudaev's leadership.
    - Theater Square speeches, Groznyĭ, 1993 July 13 (Box-folder 35: 6)
      See Box 5, Folder 4 for transcripts.
    - Daud and Roma on Chechen domestic politics, 1993 August 24 (Box-folder 35: 7)
    - Dzhokhar Dudaev television interview, 1994 February 12 (Box-folder 35: 8)
    - Ruslan Martagov, 1994 October 2 (Box-folder 35: 9)
      Topics include Russian-Chechen relations, Chechen domestic politics, and opposition movements.
    - Ruslan Zakriev, 1994 October 24 (Box-folder 35: 10)
      See Box 4, Folder 20 for transcripts.
    - Abdula Bugaev, 1994 October 29 and December 3 (Box-folder 35: 11-12)
      See Box 3, Folder 25 for transcripts.
    - Ruslan Labazanov on Chechen domestic politics, 1994 October 30 (Box-folder 35: 13)
      Also includes a report on the 1994 CIS summit in Moscow.
    - Isa Aliroev, 1994 November (Box-folder 35: 14)
      See Box 3, Folder 16 for partial transcript.
    - Umar Avturkhanov on Chechen domestic politics, 1994 November 8, undated (Box-folder 35: 15-16)
      Includes an interview with an unidentified man on Lithuanian citizenship for Russians.
    - Speeches by Sheikh Dzhamo and Aslambek Aslakhanov at a conference on Chechen politics, 1994 November 25 (Box-folder 35: 17)
      Side B includes a speech by Mikhail Gorbachev.
    - Chechen diaspora conference speeches and panels, 1994 November 28 (Box-folder 35: 18)
      Begins with a Voice of America report on the Chechen diaspora.
    - Aslambek Aslakhanov press conference on the situation in Chechnia, 1994 November 28 (Box-folder 35: 19)
    - Khadzhi-Murat Ibragimbeĭli on Chechen domestic affairs, 1994 December (Box-folder 35: 20)
      Side B features an interview with Iavus Akhmadov on Russian and Chechen politics.
    - Ramzan Dagaev, 1994 December (Box-folder 35: 21)
      On Chechen domestic politics, particularly the opposition to Dzhokhar Dudaev. Interview recorded on a drive around Groznyĭ.
    - Dzhokhar Dudaev and Sultan Geliskhanov press conference, 1994 December 1 (Box-folder 35: 22)
    - Television report on a visit by Russian deputies to Groznyĭ, 1994 December 3 (Box-folder 35: 23)
    - Salambek Khadzhiev, 1994 December 6 (Box-folder 35: 24)
      On his opposition to Dzhokhar Dudaev and the importance of free elections in Chechnia.
    - Groznyĭ refugees in Znamenskoe, 1994 December 19 (Box-folder 35: 25)